Thomas G. Paterson Papers
© 2003 University of Connecticut
- Series III: Lectures and Panels, undated, 1964-2002
  - "The World in Aiken's Times: The Rise and Decline of the United States", University of Vermont, Aiken Lecture Series (26 October 1991), undated, 1991 April - October (Box 7:177)
  - "How the Cold War Ended", Campbell University (24 March 1992), undated (Box 7:178)
  - "The End of the Cold War and the Illusive Quest for Peace", Richard E. Welch, Jr. Memorial Lecture, Lafayette College (28 April 1992), undated (Box 7:179)
  - "TGP's Intellectual Journey"; "Writing Cold War History"; "Narrative Account of Career: Thomas G. Paterson", Williams College (November 1992), undated, 1992 November (Box 7:180)
  - "The End of the Cold War and the Illusive Quest for Peace", lecture trip to Venezuela (January 1993), undated, 1986-1993 (Box 7:181)
    - Ephemera: printed napkin and periodicals, undated, 1995 (Box 30:782)
  - "The End of the Cold War and U.S. Foreign Relations", New England History Teachers Association (4 March 1993), undated, 1992 October 27 (Box 7:182)
  - "Spinning Out of Control: JFK's War Against Cuba and the Missile Crisis", Sharp Symposium, Southern Methodist University (8 November 1993, Dallas, Texas), undated (Box 7:183)
  - "U.S. Decline and Renewal in the New World Order", commencement address, Mt. Senario College (21 May 1994), undated (Box 7:184)
  - "U.S. Intervention in Cuba, 1898: Historiography on the Spanish-American-Cuban-Filipino War", Havana, Cuba (June 1994), undated (Box 7:185)
  - "Spinning Out of Control: U.S.-Cuban Relations From Missile Crisis to Refugee Crisis", Stonehill College (2 November 1994), undated, 1994 (Box 7:186)
  - "Caribbean Neighbors: The Cold War Legacy of Contesting Castro", T. Paterson keynote speaker at conference "The United States and its Caribbean Neighbors" (7 December 1994), 1994 November - December (Box 7:187)
  - "The Limits of Hegemony: The United States and the Cuban Revolution", lecture trip to Cartagena University (Colombia, 1995), undated, 1994-1996 (Box 7:188)
  - "The Making of a Cold War Historian", Colorado State University (1995), undated (Box 7:189)
  - "The Foreign Relations of Baseball", Colorado State University (February 1995), undated, 1994-1995 (Box 7:190)
  - "Spinning Out of Control: JFK's War Against Cuba and the Missile Crisis", Colorado State University (February 1995), undated (Box 8:191)
  - Opening remarks for "World War II: Unintended Consequences", U.S. Naval Institute (26 April 1995, Annapolis, Maryland), undated, 1993-1995 (Box 8:192)
  - "Democratization, Peace, and Human Rights in Latin America", University of Connecticut Symposium (18 October 1995), undated, 1987-1995 (Box 8:193)
  - "The Limits of Hegemony: The United States and the Cuban Revolution", Yale University (24 April 1996), undated (Box 8:194)
  - Dow Visiting Professor, Saginaw Valley State University Correspondence, 1997 (Box 8:195)
  - "The Making of a Cold War Historian - and Contesting Castro", Trent University (1997), undated (Box 8:196)
  - "U.S. Foreign Policy in a New Era", Idaho State University (26 February 1997), 1985-1997 (Box 8:197)
  - "The Limits of Hegemony: The United States and the Cuban Revolution; U.S.-Cuba - What Went Wrong?", Trent University (March 1997), 1996-1997 (Box 8:198)
  - Presentation on the Marshall Plan, World Affairs Council (8 May 1997), undated, 1997 January - March (Box 8:199)
  - "Dr. Strangelove lecture", Saginaw Valley State University (October 1997), undated, 1964-1967 (Box 8:200)
  - "Intellectual Journey and Approaches to History", Saginaw Valley State University (October 1997), undated (Box 8:201)
  - "Race and Foreign Relations", Saginaw Valley State University (October 1997), undated, 1998 November (Box 8:202)
  - "The United States and Cuba: What Went Wrong?", Fairfield University (19 November 1997), undated (Box 8:203)
  - "The Limits of Hegemony: U.S.-Cuba Relations Since the 1950's", Ohio State University (14 April 1998), 1997-1998 (Box 8:204)
  - Meeting with cadets, U.S. Coast Guard Academy (29 October 1999), undated (Box 8:205)
- Series IV: University of Connecticut files, undated, 1967-2002
  - Student evaluations of Paterson's teaching, 1968-1979 (Box 8:206)
  - Student evaluations of Paterson's teaching, 1980-1992 (Box 8:207)
  - Student evaluations of Paterson's teaching, 1994-1996 (Box 8:208)
  - Ph.D. field exam questions (1970-1995), undated, 1970-1995 (Box 8:209)
  - Foreign Policy Seminars
    - Correspondence (Box 8:210)
    - Correspondence, 1993-1997 (Box 8:211)
    - Seminar summaries, 1986-1993 (Box 8:212)
    - Seminar summaries, undated, 1993-1996 (Box 8:213)
    - First foreign policy seminar (22 November 1985), undated, 1985 November 22 (Box 8:214)
    - Second foreign policy seminar (21 February 1986), 1985-1986 (Box 8:215)
    - Third foreign policy seminar (18 April 1986), undated, 1984-1986 (Box 8:216)
    - Fourth foreign policy seminar (31 October 1986), 1986 March - October (Box 8:217)
    - Fifth foreign policy seminar (5 December 1986), 1986 November - December (Box 8:218)
    - Sixth foreign policy seminar (6 February 1987), 1986-1987 (Box 8:219)
    - Seventh foreign policy seminar (6 March 1987), 1986-1987 (Box 8:220)
    - Eighth foreign policy seminar (27 March 1987), 1987 January - March (Box 8:221)
    - Ninth foreign policy seminar (23 October 1987), 1987 April - October (Box 8:222)
    - Tenth foreign policy seminar (19 February 1988), 1988 January - February (Box 8:223)
    - Foreign Policy Seminar, 2002 November 15 (Box 31:785)
  - Department of History Placement Committee (1994-1995), undated, 1994-1996 (Box 8:224)
  - Development Committee, Department of History (1996-1997), T. Paterson chairman, 1996-1997 (Box 8:225)
  - Dodd Papers acquisition, 1985-1986 (Box 31:786)
- Series V: Professional activities, undated, 1967-2002
  - T. Paterson's involvement in University of Connecticut campus peace activities (anti-Vietnam) and demonstrations (1968), undated, 1967-1969 (Box 8:226)
  - Thomas Y. Crowell American History Project (abortive) (1972-1974), undated, 1969-1974 (Box 8:227)
  - Telluride Association summer program, Cornell University, T. Paterson and Clifford (1974), undated, 1974 March - September (Box 8:228)
  - Cold War Crises lecture series (not offered) (1975), undated, 1975-1977 (Box 8:229)
  - College of Social Studies, Wesleyan University examiner (1975), undated, 1973-1975 (Box 8:230)
  - Research grant applications, undated, 1975-1978 (Box 9:231)
  - Telluride Association summer program, Cornell University (1976), undated, 1975-1977 (Box 9:232)
  - Organization of American Historians program committee (1977), undated, 1975-1977 (Box 9:233)
  - T.V. program: Cold War, 1979-1980 (Box 9:234)
  - Colby College History Department chairmanship: declined, undated, 1980-1982 (Box 9:235)
  - Vietnam veterans oral history project: Puzzo (1980-1982), undated, 1981-1982 (Box 9:236)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities summer seminars directed by T. Paterson (1980, 1983), undated, 1980-1984 (Box 9:237)
  - Committee to search for editor of Diplomatic History, Society for Historians of American Foreign Relations (SHAFR), undated, 1981-1982 (Box 9:238)
  - Cold War film project: Are We Winning...?, 1980-1987 (Box 9:239)
  - Fellowship: Institute for the Study of World Politics, undated, 1982-1984 (Box 9:240)
  - American Philosophical Society research grant, undated, 1983-1984 (Box 9:241)
  - History disc: Cuban Missile Crisis (abortive project), undated, 1983-1984 (Box 9:242)
  - Chinese scholars
    - General information related to Chinese students, undated, 1985-1987 (Box 9:243)
    - Correspondence with Xu Guoqi about study in the United States, undated, 1987-1991 (Box 9:244)
    - Correspondence with various Chinese scholars before and after 1987 lecture trip
      - undated, 1985-1987 (Box 9:245)
      - 1988-1989 (Box 9:246)
      - 1990-1994 (Box 9:247)
    - Correspondence with Wang Li about study in the United States, undated, 1987-1994 (Box 9:248)
    - Correspondence with Du Yaoguang (Donald), T. Paterson's assistant for study in the United States, undated, 1988-1993 (Box 9:249)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities fellowship, undated, 1983-1985 (Box 9:250)
  - Board of editors, Journal of American History
    - Correspondence, recommendations, etc. (1985-1988)
      - undated, 1984-1986 (Box 9:251)
      - 1986-1988 (Box 9:252)
      - undated, 1985-1988 (Box 9:253)
    - T. Paterson's critiques of articles submitted, undated, 1985-1988 (Box 9:254)
  - T. Paterson's Presidency of the Society for Historians of American Foreign Relations (SHAFR),1986-1988
    - Correspondence, undated, 1985-1987 (Box 9:255)
    - Correspondence, 1987 January - March (Box 9:256)
    - Correspondence, 1987 March - June (Box 10:257)
    - Correspondence, 1987 July - 1988 March (Box 10:258)
    - Administrative records, undated, 1985-1987 (Box 10:259)
  - Trip to Soviet Union (1987) and contacts in USSR and Russia, undated, 1986-1990 (Box 10:260)
  - Advisory Board, American National Biography, ACLS and Oxford University Press, undated, 1987-1995 (Box 10:261)
  - Correspondence regarding possible lectures in China, undated, 1985-1989 (Box 10:262)
  - Guggenheim fellowship (1991), undated, 1990-1992 (Box 10:263)
  - Marshall Plan film, undated, 1991-1993 (Box 10:264)
  - Monhegan Emergency Rescue Service (MERS) Chowderfest, undated, 1992-1996 (Box 10:265)
  - Latin American Studies Association (LASA) task force, Cuba (1995), undated, 1994 March 2 (Box 10:266)
  - Proposal to Houghton Mifflin for grant to Stonehill College (1996), undated, 1993-1996 (Box 10:267)
  - Correspondence,2002 (Box 31:783-784)
- Series VI: Research materials, undated, 1839-1997
  - Notes, Documents, Essays: U.S. Foreign Relations Topics
    - American Diplomatic History: Themes and Questions; Historiography, 1962-1994 (Box 10:268)
    - American Isolationism and Isolationists, undated (Box 10:269)
    - The American Response to the Bolshevik Revolution, undated (Box 10:270)
    - The Aroostook War and the Northeastern boundary dispute (includes papers by T. Paterson: "The Aroostook War and the Northeastern Boundary Dispute" (1963); "Maine's Only and Own International War"), undated, 1839-1982 (Box 10:271)
    - Baseball and foreign relations, undated, 1977-1994 (Box 10:272)
    - Bibliography (tabbed) for mss and oral histories (Tray 1), undated (Box 32)
    - Carter foreign policy, undated, 1976-1985 (Box 10:273)
    - China and non-recognition, undated, 1988-1992 (Box 10:274)
    - Civil War (American Civil War) diplomacy, undated, 1860-1977 (Box 10:275)
    - Cold War, undated1972-1992 (Box 10:276)
    - Cold War--Organized research notes for early Cold War period (Tray 4), undated (Box 35)
    - Cold War--Unorganized research notes for early Cold War period (Tray 2-3) (Box 32-35)
    - Coming of World War II: Germany and general, undated, 1950 (Box 10:277)
    - Diplomacy in the 1920s, undated, 1921-1981 (Box 10:278)
    - Eastern Europe and origins of the Cold War, including Yalta and Potsdam, undated, 1947-1982 (Box 10:279)
    - Eisenhower-Dulles, undated, 1970-1987 (Box 10:280)
    - Glossary: Nuclear Arms Race, undated, 1974-1985 (Box 10:281)
    - Imperialism and the Spanish-American War, undated, 1994-1995 (Box 10:282)
    - Kennan, George F., undated, 1950 November (Box 10:283)
    - John F. Kennedy and his foreign policy
      - Articles, writings by T. Paterson (includes: "Introduction: John F. Kennedy's Quest for Victory and the Global Crisis"; "John F. Kennedy's Foreign Policy: The Perils of a Cold Warrior"; "The Kennedy Years Foreign Policy"; "Action Intellectuals: The Foreign Policy of John F. Kennedy"; "John F. Kennedy and the Cuban Missile Crisis"; "The Gloss is Dulled: JFK's Foreign Policy after 25 Years"; "JFK and the Vietnam War"), undated, 1992 (Box 10:284)
      - Notes, undated, 1986-1987 (Box 11:285)
      - Photocopies of documents related to Soviet Union, 1960-1982 (Box 11:286)
      - Papers (not by T. Paterson), 1972-1993 (Box 11:287)
      - Published articles (not by T. Paterson), undated, 1962-1978 (Box 11:288)
      - Published articles (not by T. Paterson), 1979-1988 (Box 11:289)
      - Published articles (not by T. Paterson), 1989-1996 (Box 11:290)
    - Korean War, undated, 1982-1995 (Box 11:291)
    - Late 19th century diplomacy, undated, 1936-1984 (Box 11:292)
    - Manifest Destiny and Mexican War, 1982 (Box 11:293)
    - Monroe Doctrine (and John Quincy Adams), undated, 1984-1986 (Box 11:294)
    - Nixon-Ford-Kissinger foreign policy, undated, 1969-1986 (Box 11:295)
    - Origins of the Cold War, 1943-1990 (Box 11:296)
    - Origins of the Cold War: Maddox controversy, undated, 1973-1975 (Box 11:297)
    - Postwar Planning, undated, 1943 (Box 11:298)
    - Reagan foreign policy, undated, 1980-1991 (Box 11:299)
    - Research notes for various projects, organized by subject (Tray 11), undated (Box 41-42)
    - Senate Select Committee intelligence activities, Covert Action in Chile, 1975 December (Box 11:300)
    - Soviet-American relations: 1919 to World War II, undated (Box 11:301)
    - Stalin and America, by Constantine Pleshak, undated, 1989-1990 (Box 11:302)
    - Statistics on world economy, U.S. place and rankings, undated, 1975-1992 (Box 11:303)
    - "Truman Doctrine", Research notes organized by subject (Tray 6), undated
    - U.S., FDR, and the coming of World War II, undated, 1969-1993 (Box 11:304)
    - Versailles, undated, 1930 (Box 11:305)
    - Wilsonianism and World War I, undated, 1954-1996 (Box 11:306)
    - World War II: foreign and military relations, undated, 1942-1944 (Box 11:307)
  - Allen, George V.
    - Allen memoirs (with footnotes by T. Paterson), undated (Box 12:308)
    - "Mission to Iran, 1946-1948: Ambassador George V. Allen's Memoirs", ed. T. Paterson (draft; not published), undated (Box 12:309)
    - Correspondence, undated, 1967-1976 (Box 12:310)
    - Research materials, undated, 1944-1973 (Box 12:311)
    - Allen's correspondence (copies), 1948-1969 (Box 12:312)
    - Allen photographs, undated, 1946-1968 (Box 12:313)
  - American-Russian Chamber of Commerce, 1970-1971 (Box 12:314)
  - International Trade Organization (research materials for unpublished article), undated (Box 12:315)
  - International Trade Organization, undated, 1945-1946 (Box 12:316)
  - International Trade Organization, 1946-1977 (Box 12:317)
  - Johnston, Eric, in Russia, 1944, undated, 1944-1973 (Box 12:318)
  - Morse, Wayne (senator of Oregon), undated, 1946-1975 (Box 12:319)
  - Parsons, J. Graham research project (abortive), undated, 1985-1986 (Box 12:320)
  - Truman Doctrine
    - Greece and relations with the U.S.
      - London Times index, 1944-1950 (Box 12:321)
      - Documents; articles, undated, 1944-1960 (Box 12:322)
      - Documents; articles, 1947-1949 (Box 12:323)
      - Documents; articles, 1949-1979 (Box 12:324)
      - Various papers by John Iatrides and Henry B. Ryan, undated, 1974-1975 (Box 12:325)
      - Deadline Data on World Affairs fact cards, 1974 January 4-18 (Box 12:326)
    - Iran (Persia) relations with the U.S.
      - London Times index, 1944-1950 (Box 13:327)
      - Documents, articles, 1943-1945 (Box 13:328)
      - Documents, articles, 1946-1975 (Box 13:329)
      - Deadline Data on World Affairs fact cards, 107-1974 (Box 13:330)
    - Turkey and relations with the U.S.
      - London Times index, 1944-1950 (Box 13:331)
      - Documents, articles, undated, 1946-1979 (Box 13:332)
      - Deadline Data on World Affairs fact cards, 1972-1974 (Box 13:333)
    - Documents from foreign office--Correspondence (FO371), Public Records Office, London, England
      - Microfiche (Box 13:334)
      - 1945 December 27 - 1946 Dececember 12 (Box 13:335)
      - 1946 Feb ruary 17-25 (Box 13:336)
      - 1946 February 23 - Mar 26 (Box 13:337)
      - 1946 March 30 - April 5 (Box 13:338)
      - 1946 May 25-30 (Box 13:339)
      - 1946 July 5 - August 8 (Box 13:340)
      - 1946 September - October (Box 13:341)
      - 1946 September 6 - November 5 (Box 13:342)
      - 1946 October 25-30 (Box 13:343)
      - 1946 November - December 12 (Box 13:344)
      - 1946 November 13 - 1978 February 8 (Box 13:345)
      - 1946 November 27 - December 12 (Box 13:346)
      - 1946 December - 1947 January 16 (Box 13:347)
    - Drafting the speech (Truman Doctrine), undated, 1947-1973 (Box 13:348)
    - Congressional Record
      - Notes on Congressional Record appendix, v. 93, Mar 12 - May 25, 1947, undated (Box 13:349)
      - Photocopies of CR
        - 1947 March 12-31 (Box 13:350)
        - 1947 April 1-10 (Box 13:351)
        - 1947 April 11-18 (Box 13:352)
        - 1947 April 21-22 (Box 13:353)
        - 1947 April 23-29 (Box 13:354)
        - 1947 May 6-7 (Box 13:355)
        - 1947 May 8-9 (Box 13:356)
        - 1947 May 12-19 (Box 13:357)
    - Reactions to Truman Doctrine speech, 1947-1981 (Box 13:358)
    - Truman Doctrine research completed, undated, 1966-1981 (Box 13:359)
  - Middle East; Suez issue
    - Middle East and Suez issue before July 1956, undated, 1950-1982 (Box 14:360)
    - Middle East and Suez issue, July - September 1956, 1956-1989 (Box 14:361)
    - Suez crisis (invasion), October-November 1956, 1956-1967 (Box 14:362)
    - Eisenhower Doctrine, 1956 December (Box 14:363)
    - Drafts of speech and resolution for Eisenhower Doctrine, 1956-1957 (Box 14:364)
    - President's meeting with Congressional leaders, 1957 January 1 (Box 14:365)
    - Eisenhower Doctrine, undated, 1957 January (Box 14:366)
    - Eisenhower Doctrine, 1957 February (Box 14:367)
    - U.S.-Middle East, undated, 1957 March - May (Box 14:368)
    - U.S.-Middle East, 1957 August - December (Box 14:369)
    - U.S.-Middle East (excluding Lebanon), 1958 (Box 14:370)
    - NSC 5801/1 National Security Council: Long Range U.S. Policy Toward the Near East, 1958 January 24 (Box 14:371)
    - Intervention in Lebanon
      - Documents, 1958 (Box 14:372)
      - Documents, 1958 July 1-16 (Box 14:373)
      - Documents, 1958-1960 (Box 14:374)
      - Articles, book chapters, pamphlets, undated, 1958-1983 (Box 14:375)
    - NSC 5820/1 U.S. Policy Toward the Near East, 1958 November 4 (Box 14:376)
  - United States and Castro's Cuba
    - [This portion of the collection has been microfilmed by Scholarly Resources (1998) and is available in the Babbidge Library Reference Microform Collection.]
    - U.S. Embassy-Havana weekly reports (JOINT WEEKA)
      - 1956 December 5 - 1957 February 27 (Box 14:377)
      - 1957 March 5 - July 31 (Box 14:378)
      - 1957 August 7 - December (Box 14:379)
      - 1958 January 1 - June 25 (Box 14:380)
      - 1958 July 2 - December 30 (Box 14:381)
      - 1959 January 7 - July 1 (Box 14:382)
      - 1959 July 7 - September 29 (Box 14:383)
      - 1959 October 6 - December 29 (Box 14:384)
      - 1960 January 5 - June 29 (Box 15:385)
      - 1960 July 6 -September 24 (Box 15:386)
      - 1960 October 3 - December 30 (Box 15:387)
    - Chronology, U.S.-Cuba Relations, 1957-1963, by Senate Foreign Relations Committee, 1963 (Box 15:388)
    - Republican Congressional Committee, The Cuban Issue: A Chronology, 1963 May (Box 15:389)
    - U.S. Officials responsible for U.S.-Cuban relations (from U.S. Government Manual), 1953-1969 (Box 15:390)
    - List of U.S. ambassadors to Cuba (with dates of service), undated (Box 15:391)
    - Members, Senate Foreign Relations Committee and House Foreign Affairs Committee, undated (Box 15:392)
    - U.S. Officials stationed in Cuba (Foreign Service list), 1956-1961 (Box 15:393)
    - American military personnel in Cuba and U.S. military role, 1955-1985 (Box 15:394)
    - Biographies of U.S. and Cuban leaders, 1958-1979 (Box 15:395)
    - Documents from Cuban Archives, Havana (U.S.-Cuban military affairs), 1956-1958 (Box 15:396)
    - American businesses in Cuba (Hersey), undated, 1945-1985 (Box 15:397)
    - Eugene Desvernine on Cuba, undated, 1985 March - May (Box 15:398)
    - Export-Import Bank and Cuba, 1955-1960 (Box 15:399)
    - American businesses in Cuba (Braga Brother Collection, University of Florida), undated, 1955-1960 (Box 15:400)
    - Ford Motor Company in Cuba, 1951-1960 (Box 15:401)
    - Sears, Roebuck in Cuba, 1959-1961 (Box 15:402)
    - Texaco and Cuba, undated, 1957-1960 (Box 15:403)
    - LaCharite Study of Cuba, 1953-1959, 1963 September (Box 15:404)
    - Cataloging forms, Cuba folder, Country files, Nixon pre-Presidential papers, 1955-1959, undated, 1993 April 22 (Box 15:405)
    - "Draft White Paper" (1950s events) and update; Department of State, undated, 1959 May 12 (Box 15:406)
    - Jules DuBois, 1945-1965 (Box 15:407)
    - Merwin Bohan's correspondence, Harry S. Truman Library (HSTL), 1971-1973 (Box 15:408)
    - Milton Eisenhower oral interview, 1967 September 6 (Box 15:409)
    - Russia is Winning, mss Ch. XIV, William D. Pawley, undated, 1974 (Box 15:410)
    - William D. Pawley; FBI records, 1945-1984 (Box 15:411)
    - Miro Cardona, undated (Box 15:412)
    - Justo Carillo's Recollections, undated (Box 15:413)
    - Justo Carillo lecture on U.S.-Cuba relations, 1902-1955, 1985 (Box 15:414)
    - Robert Stevenson oral history, 1989 September 9 (Box 15:415)
    - Instituto Cultural Cubano-Norte-Americano, undated, 1943-1961 (Box 15:416)
    - U.S. Trade With Cuba, 1960-1963, U.S. Department of Commerce, 1964 May (Box 15:417)
    - World Trade With Cuba, 1961-1962, U.S. Department of Commerce, 1964 March (Box 15:418)
    - Efforts to restrict trade between American allies and Cuba, undated, 1962-1965 (Box 16:419)
    - John Crimmons oral history, 1989 May 10 (Box 16:420)
    - Office of Coordinator of Cuban Affairs in Miami (Harvey Summ notes), 1982 March 25 (Box 16:421)
    - Malcolm Moos interview with Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1966 November 8 (Box 16:422)
    - Plots to Assassinate Fidel Castro, CIA report, 1967 May 23 (Box 16:423)
    - The CIA's Secret Army, CBS reports, 1977 June 10 (Box 16:424)
    - Cuban military status: data from Institute for Strategic Studies (London), 1962-1970 (Box 16:425)
    - Department of State Administrative History, Ch. 6, LBJ Library, undated (Box 16:426)
    - Public Papers of the Presidents: Kennedy, 1961-1963 (Box 16:427)
    - Presidential statements on Cuba, 1962-1963 (Box 16:428)
    - Lyndon B. Johnson statements on Cuba (public papers), 1963-1968 (Box 16:429)
    - Richard M. Nixon statements on Cuba (public papers), 1969-1973 (Box 16:430)
    - The Cuban Report (Cuban student directorate in English), 1962-1965 (Box 16:431)
    - Che Guevara, subversion, Bolivia and Latin America, undated, 1964-1971 (Box 16:432)
    - Cuba-U.S., pre-1956 relations, 1942-1959 (Box 16:433)
    - U.S.-Cuba 1956 (general), 1956-1958 (Box 16:434)
    - Anti-Batista groups in the U.S., undated, 1956 (Box 16:435)
    - Anti-Batista groups in the U.S., undated, 1956-1957 (Box 16:436)
    - Cuba, December 1956, undated, 1956-1957 (Box 16:437)
    - Cuba, 1957, undated, 1957-1958 (Box 16:438)
    - U.S.-Cuba, January-February, 1957, undated, 1957 January - March (Box 16:439)
    - Anti-Batists groups in Los Angeles, 1957-1959 (FBI records), undated, 1957-1959 (Box 16:440)
    - Departure of U.S. Ambassador Gardner, 1957 January - June (Box 16:441)
    - Herbert Matthews trip to Cuba and interview with Fidel Castro, February, 1957, undated, 1957-1977 (Box 16:442)
    - U.S.-Cuba, March, 1957, 1957-1958 (Box 16:443)
    - U.S.-Cuba, April, 1957, 1957-1958 (Box 16:444)
    - U.S.-Cuba, May, 1957, 1957 May - July (Box 16:445)
    - U.S.-Cuba, June-July, 1957, undated, 1957 June - November (Box 16:446)
    - Anti-Batista activities in the U.S., undated, 1957 June - August (Box 16:447)
    - U.S.-Cuba, August, 1957, 1957 July - August (Box 17:448)
    - U.S.-Cuba, September, 1957, undated, 1957 September (Box 17:449)